Wait, wait. Hold up.
Sorry, I don't quite follow.
You're talking about
the three days leading up to the event?
-Yes, all this time.
-All right, sorry. Got it.
What did you think we were talking about?
But just to be clear…
This does all link back up
with how Makina ended up like this?
Yeah…
-Okay, start again from the top.
-Ugh!
Hold it, hold it. Just a moment.
This is your report on the three days
leading up to the runaway train?
-Yes! How many times do I have to--
-I know it doesn't make sense, but if--
All right, all right. Just--
One at a time, please!
Sorry, please start from the top.
-Ugh! Again? Really?
-From the top?
3 DAYS AGO, NEO MACHIDA POLICE STATION
12 HOURS AFTER CHIHARU AND MAKINA'S ARREST
Hey Makina, we're so out of place here.
Don't look at them.
-Look at those two. So shady.
-I said don't look.
We live in different worlds.
I'm scared. Won't they start a fight?
Then stop looking.
Okay, thanks for waiting.
If you're in this room, that means
you were recently arrested around here.
I'm going to call your names
and reason for arrest.
Let me know if I get anything wrong.
-Max MacCallister?
-Yes.
-Kurt Cramer?
Here on possession of illegal sugar?
-Yes.
-Yep.
-Kanata Iwao?
-Me.
Akane Daidoji?
Yes.
-Here for speeding?
-Yes.
-Chiharu Kujo.
-Makina Kurusu.
-Yes.
Speeding, obstruction of police,
and blowing up a patrol car.
-Yes.
Seriously?
-Blowing up a patrol car?
-I heard about that.
What an insane line-up.
Okay, now everyone take a look
at the printout you have in front of you.
You'll see they include details on
the program you are about to take part in.
-Max would you read the first line?
-Huh?
Um, "Community Service Program.
The Ginkyo Police Department,
under the jurisdiction of the
United Stars of Barnadia…"
"Completion of the sentence
is subject to the assessment of
the supervising officer."
Okay, good job, everyone.
Now, everyone understand the program?
-Not at all.
-So we work here now?
-I hate legalese.
-In turns, please!
-How do we complete this anyway?
-Quiet. Quiet.
So basically the prison's full,
so we gotta serve our sentence
through community service?
Yeah, that's about it.
-Then just say so.
-You understood all this?
-Quiet please.
-Hey, my desk is wobbly.
Are there any questions?
-I have one.
-Yes, Ms. Kujo.
How long do we have to
do this community service?
You'll generally be here for about a week.
-That's far too long!
-I expected just five hours!
-A week?
-Okay, be quiet, everyone. Shut up.
-Any other questions?
-Here.
What is it?
What exactly are we doing
for this "community service"?
I said-- oh, that's actually
a pretty valid question.
This here is the Galactic Limited Express,
otherwise known as the Milky Subway.
Its official name is the AM24.
It was made by Titan Industry
in the earth calendar year 72,
and it is now managed
by Chubu Railway Company.
As you can see, it's become very dirty
over many years of continuous use.
As such, your job today
is to clean the carriages.
"Clean Up The Milky Subway."
This is your community service.
-Yuck, I didn't expect this.
-Well, this is a pain.
Enough!
I will now announce
the carriages assigned to each team.
Kurt and Max. Carriages three and four.
Kanata and Akane. Carriages five and six.
Which leaves carriages seven and eight
for you ladies.
Carriages one and two have escape pods
and other precision equipment,
so we'll leave them for someone else.
Go on then. Get to work.
-Ugh, I don't wanna do this.
-This is like being back at school.
Where are you two going?
-Take a dump.
-Take a leak.
Literally child labor.
-Well, shall we get started?
-Yeah.
We'll start from… Wait.
Whoa, is that a Chronos CP?
I don't believe this!
What's so great about that?
Titan used to make these
all-purpose control panels at one point,
but the default defense systems sucked ass
so their cost-effectiveness was really--
-What about this?
-Hm?
-Oh, that's O.T.A.M.
-O.T.A.M.?
She's the Outer-space
Transportation Animatronics Manager.
She was supposed to speak using AI,
but I guess she wasn't popular
and they stopped using her.
Really…
Hey, can she talk?
-I doubt it. She's probably broken.
-Hello? Hello? Talk to me.
-Hey, Chi. Come look at this.
-What is it?
Come look at this symbol.
-Hm? It can turn into a robot?
-Yeah.
All vehicles with Chronos CPs can do it.
-But I can't imagine how--
-Thank you for using…
Whoa!
Ugh, don't scare me.
What are they doing in there?
Oops! Sorry, boss.
-Boss?
-There's blood.
-So, this train we're about to clean.
-Yeah?
You heard
that weird urban legend about it?
Nah.
Well, they say
there was another group of inmates
cleaning up the train
on community service,
just like we're about to do.
And?
Well, they all started killing each other.
All sorts of crazy shit started happening.
You don't say.
So they say the train's cursed,
or something like that.
Hmm…
-That's real scary.
-It is, isn't it?
Hey, O.T.A.M.
O.T.A.M. What's today's weather?
T-Today, Shin-Shin-Kisaragi, G-Ginkyo
will be s-sunny--
Hey, O.T.A.M.
-O.T.A.M. Calm down.
-Stop playing with her.
-She's so cute!
-That's not cute at all.
And hey, this train's gotta be completely
busted if O.T.A.M.'s in such a state.
Why's that?
Well, the main computer's gotta be busted,
which means
this train's not exactly safe to run.
Oh, wow.
I know they sometimes ran these things
without the proper safety checks.
-Yeah?
-Confirming safety checks.
-All aboard.
-That's kinda scary. Huh?
-What?
-Huh?
What was that?
Huh?
Oh no!
Asami!
Asami! Asami!
Uh, the train… the train!
It just… started moving!
The detain-- not detainees.
The, uh, the inmates!
The inmates are in there!
They're gone without a supervisor!
I dunno where they're going!
-You know, you got me into this.
-Huh?
We were both done for speeding,
but you were the driver.
Yeah, but I only sped
because of your music--
You sped up when the police came
and shot down one of their robots.
-I panicked, okay?
-You still can't do that!
I never wanted to drive
in the first place.
You made me, which means it's your fault.
Shall I get the popcorn?
4 DAYS AGO
2 HOURS AFTER CHIHARU AND MAKINA'S ARREST
Sorry to keep you waiting.
Your background checks took a while.
And Makina, you come
from a good family, don't you?
My family's got nothing to do with this.
Well, I guess not.
And this isn't your first encounter
with the police, now, is it?
Ah… No, it's not.
I found your mugshots in our database.
This is you from fifth grade, yes?
-Wow, that takes me back.
-What were we in for?
-Isn't that from when you knocked Ken out?
-Oh, Ken Izu?
This Ken. Was he the male victim?
Yeah. Chiharu's ex.
He was a right piece of shit.
-Was he?
-Oh, he wasn't that bad.
He left Chiharu waiting for six hours.
He totally stood her up.
-Sounds like trash.
-You see? Pure trash.
He's not trash. He said he caught a cold.
-So I punched his lights out.
-That was wrong.
-You're always so violent.
-Stand up for yourself!
All right, that's enough.
And how about this one? Same issue?
-Makina nearly killed some seniors.
-I'm tellin' ya, that was self-defense!
-You sent five students to the hospital.
-Pft. Babies.
I kinda felt sorry for them.
They just flirted with me.
They were not flirting.
You were in real danger.
It's true they didn't exactly
have the best of records.
You see? I was right.
-So I beat them good.
-Still wrong.
Why do you have to be so violent?
It's honestly freaky.
Who's gonna look out for you
if not me, huh?
When Furukawa broke your PIKOPO?
You never told him!
He said he was real sorry after.
But he never paid for--
What's this?
We hand these out at the local schools.
I get the feeling you two could use these.
You calling me a schoolkid?
Why do I need one? She's the one
always dragging me into a mess.
Your friend who won't listen
to anyone but you,
so it's up to you
to tell her "no" sometimes.
See? It's your--
You're too quick to judge others.
Be kind to--
But she only ever attracts jerks.
Makina, listen.
You've been arrested 17 times.
That makes you a jerk, too.
If you don't fix your ways soon,
nobody's gonna help you when you need it.
I don't need help.
-You might one day.
-Never.
-But what if you do?
-I won't!
-I do…
-We're in trouble.
Hey… wait!
We are in big trouble here!
Calm down, it's okay.
-I think I can drive this thing.
-You're the best!
-We've got the control keys, yeah?
-Yeah.
There's one missing.
If there's one missing, then that means…
-It must be in the driver's cab.
-What do you mean?
I'm saying… Never mind!
We've gotta get to the first carriage
to get the key to stop this thing.
-Get to the first carriage, yeah?
-Yes!
-First carriage?
-First carriage!
Yes, this is Haga.
Oh, hi there. This is Kanzaki.
Um…
We've got a runaway train with inmates
on board. We're looking for it. Over.
You know that's not gonna cut it.
Huh? No, this is fine.
It's fine. It's not fine…
-This is Kanzaki.
-What the hell was that?!
You expect me to greenlight
a search with just that call?
-Sorry, sir.
-Sort your evidence first!
Huh? You want us to come back?
Of course I do, you idiot!
Put Asami on.
I know he's there.
-All right. Here he is.
-Hello?
-Asami! Asami!
-Yes? I'm here, sir.
-Keep an eye on Ryoko, okay?
-Yes, sir. I will.
-You're free to outrank her, okay?
-I'll watch her!
Kanzaki. I know I don't have to tell you--
Tch. Baldilocks.
You know… You treat inmates
better than you do others.
Yeah, well, you're too mean to them.
I don't like criminals.
So just gotta get
to the first carriage or something?
Well, that's what we're hoping.
Whoa, what's this carriage?
It's the dining car.
Wow.
Looks like they all still work.
Sorry, I'm a hungry guy.
-Huh? But wasn't that--
-It was me!
-I could've sworn--
-I'm a hungry guy!
What's wrong with you?
Hey, look. They've got my favorite.
-I'll bet it tastes like shit.
-Stop that.
Don't tell me you're getting it?
We don't have time for this.
Error.
-Why?
-Come on. Let's go.
No, wait…
-Error.
Come on. Let's go.
-Come on, Makina. You can fix it.
-What?
Like you always tinker with things.
-I don't wanna.
-But I'm hungry!
Chiharu.
What?
We shouldn't be wasting our time here.
We've gotta fix the train.
I don't want to spend time
with these dropkicks.
-Come on, Makina--
-Who knows what they'll do?
-We can hear you.
-Huh?
Oh, sorry. You see?
Hey. Hold up.
You think you're better than us, huh?
-What of it?
-Is it 'cause we're in a gang?
Ugh, stop provoking them.
-Makina…
-You got arrested just like we did.
-Sorry about her.
-Mm.
-You want that? Do ya?
-Go on. I dare ya!
Kanata! Kanata?
Kanata!
-What did you do to him?
-I just gave him a shock.
-You killed him?
-He's not dead!
How dare you!
Please insert cash.
Seriously?
Makina…
Please stop…
Huh?
Is that a limited-edition keychain?
You're a Minami fan?
And what if I am?
Whoa… A limited-edition sticker…
Huh…
Minami's pretty good, huh?
Yeah. I like her.
Which songs do you like?
It's not really her style,
but I like "Supernova."
Yeah, that's a good one.
Hey, aren't you hungry?
Uh, yeah.
-Liquid lunch okay?
-Sure.
-What flavor?
-Gyudon.
Okay.
Here.
-Here you are.
-Thanks.
Can I say something?
What happened?
I didn't think it matched her persona,
but it kinda grew on me…
-They're bonding over idols.
-Huh?
You can tell the song was shaped
by all that turmoil.
Yeah, definitely.
It still chokes me up
every time I listen to it, even now.
-This tastes like shit.
-It doesn't!
Yeah, this tastes like shit.
You can just leave it, you know?
Don't let the chief hear you.
Why not?
His family was poor,
so he developed a "clean plate" mentality.
Oh yeah?
They give us these
for zero-gravity work, yeah?
Yeah, but I don't eat 'em.
You see? But the chief likes to
"set an example for the rest of us."
So whatever we leave behind, he'll eat.
You don't say.
Hence the portly figure.
He used to be slim. A looker, even.
That's kind of sad.
So what was that secret feature
in the control room?
Oh, that?
The guy who designed it was really
into his robot anime,
so he added a program
at the control panel design stage
that turns the entire fuselage
into one giga robot.
-A giga robot?
-Yeah. Crazy, huh?
No one would ever greenlight that,
but Titan was axing a bunch of jobs,
and so it flew under the radar
right through to production.
That's how it made it
into the final design.
Not again…
Kanata!
-So, these things can still--
-Seriously? Time out.
What is that thing?
It's a security bot.
It gets deployed
when there's ruffians on board.
Though I guess this one's treating
everyone on board as a ruffian.
Why are all these machines acting funny?
Do you think Kanata'll be okay?
I think it's the same kind of stun gun
as mine, so he should be all right…
Damn, that music's annoying.
Yeek!
Kanata!
You could have blocked.
-Could you keep it down?
-I didn't even notice them.
Give him a few hours.
He'll come to eventually.
Well then. Problem solved.
-Have you been in here this whole time?
-Yup.
-And is the security bot up shit creek?
-Without a paddle.
-There's no way to stop it?
-Oh, there is.
So why don't you fix it then?
Don't feel like it.
-You what?
-Hey, hey.
Wanna come with us so we can--
Hey, stop stealing my meat.
Sorry, I wasn't paying attention.
You were saying?
Um, we think we can stop this train
if we can make it to the first carriage.
Don't you think we should do something?
Nah. This sounds like a "you" problem.
-Huh?
We've got about a billion ways to get out
of this thing, so we're in no hurry.
You're the ones who
need to get around that robot, not us.
Probably.
-You could help--
-Kurt!
-Sorry.
-You're killin' me here!
I almost died just before…
Let's wait for Kanata to come to.
-'Kay.
-I'll get them now.
10 MINUTES LATER
30 MINUTES LATER
-Urgh…
-This is taking forever.
50 MINUTES LATER
That's it!
I can't take it anymore!
-This is rough.
-Let's do something.
-All right. We need a plan.
-Yeah.
-This is me, this is Chi, this is Akane.
-Got it.
-And this is the robot--
-Where's the front?
Uh, the front of what?
-The train.
-Here.
-I'm the front.
-Ah, okay. Got it.
Wait, this is me?
-This is you.
-So this is Akane?
-No, that's him.
-Who's "him"?
You know… Him.
The security bot.
-Wait, where am I?
-You're here.
-And I'm here?
-Yes. Wait, no--
I think we're switching.
-Oh, I get it.
-You got it?
-I think so.
-And then it'll all work out?
-It'll all work out!
-We got this.
Okay, ready?
Three, two, one…
Son of a--
Heard anything from the lawyers?
Yeah. Just gotta keep our mouths shut
like always. We'll be out in no time.
Got it.
-Why do these guys look like cheaters--
-Yoohoo! I'm Popo Poppy.
Can I have a chat with you guys?
It'll just be between you and me,
so you can trust me
and tell me everything!
If you need to take a break,
you can use the door on your left--
Sorry, I'll stop.
5 DAYS AGO, 2 HOURS
AFTER KURT AND MAX'S ARREST
So… Kurt and… Max.
I'm not sure
what exactly it is that you do.
"Protection services"?
You do anything from rescuing
to kidnappings?
Yeah, more or less.
Like your jack-of-all-trades.
Got a boss you want taken care of?
-We can do anything--
-Sorry, murder's illegal where I'm from.
You were in pretty ordinary employment
before all this, yeah?
Things like cleaning and hospitality.
Yeah, I guess so.
So why'd you quit?
-No comment.
Okay… And now you're arrested
for smuggling sugar?
We aren't smugglers. We make deliveries.
We don't ask what's inside.
Yes, I can see that's your angle here.
Do you know the damage
sugar causes to people?
-Not our problem.
-Why should we care?
Well…
-Huh?
-Was that--
Sorry, that was me.
Mind if I fuel up?
Hey, nice. Got any for us?
Uh, suction candy okay?
Sweet. Now we're talking.
What flavor do you want?
Strawberry.
That's the stuff.
-It won't come out.
-It's stuck.
You guys are dumber than you look.
You've just injected yourselves
with interrogation devices.
-Seriously?
-What? No… No!
We use it for cyborgs. It's meant
to make you tell the truth.
That's so unfair!
And… on.
Don't you dare say anything.
The boss will--
Don't worry. I won't say anything.
Is your boss a he or a she?
-She.
Wow, it really works.
-Crap! I can't resist it!
-Then stop this interrogation!
Do you work for a drug ring?
-No.
-Crap!
-Hurry it up.
Guess that means you'll take on any work,
so long as it falls within the law.
-What about taxes? Do you pay those?
-Yes.
Well then…
Hey, what are you doing?
Hacking.
-What?
-Hurry it up!
Wait, you can't do that.
Stop that right now!
H-Hey… Wait. Wait!
Can you at least tell me why you quit
your normal jobs?
Because it was thankless work.
Huh?
Because nobody ever took
the time to say thank you.
I hated always being treated
like a machine.
Is that why you don't care
about other people?
-Yes.
Then if you were-- Whoa!
That was close.
No way we can trust her.
Can you still hear me?
-Yes.
Damn, let's go.
Pee, pee, pee, pee, pee,
pee, pee, pee, pee, pee.
What's this?
Pee pee.
-It's pants!
-Pants?
-Ugh, Kurt. You're such a fiend…
-Come on.
-Your mind's always in the gutter.
-I am not always thinking about my dick.
All right, now say "tea" ten times fast.
What's up, Akina?
-Makina.
Well… I kinda need your help.
-Aw, did the rest of your team wipe?
-Yeah.
-I'll help.
-Uh, you will?
-Sure. How much you payin'?
-You're charging?
What, you wanted us to work for free?
How much?
-I'm thinking 80 yen.
-Sounds good.
Eighty? It'll cost that much?
-We also accept installments.
-We are putting our asses on the line.
Do you always charge
such exorbitant rates?
I beg your pardon?
I couldn't give a rat's ass
where my clients come from.
If they're prepared to pay,
we'll do the work.
You pay us appropriately
for any services rendered.
No payment, no service.
We're not running a charity here.
Hey, I just got a 40 yen transfer.
Huh? Just now?
That's your deposit.
I'll pay the rest when you finish the job.
Who are you exactly?
What's it to you?
You don't give a rat's ass where I'm from.
I pay, and you work, right?
How long do you think
it'll take to override?
It's a Titan Kilroy, late model.
So 45 seconds, maybe?
-Got it. And a buffer?
-Three.
Okay.
-All right, let's do this.
-Let's do this.
-Whoa!
-Thank goodness.
-I thought I was dead there.
-Don't run!
-And the rest?
-Yeah, yeah.
-And we need a PO.
-Seriously? What a pain.
Sorry, but we need one
to keep the boss happy.
Hey, thanks a lot, you guys.
-Huh?
-What?
Huh? I mean, thanks for handling
that robot for us.
Well…
I mean… We did it for the money.
But without you guys, we would have been
stuck here, even if we did have the money.
Which means…
we should still thank you, right?
Well…
You're… welcome.
-I'll go on ahead, Makina.
-Sure.
-So for the tax--
-Never mind.
Huh?
-It wasn't really all that hard.
-Yeah.
All right then.
-Do you think we could come with you guys?
-You sure?
-Yeah, it's fine.
-Sure… Thanks.
-Hey, what about my deposit?
-No refunds.
It's a pickle, all right.
Yeah.
We've had runaway trains
with inmates on board before,
but there's no one train type
or route to connect them all.
All we can say is that it seems
to happen in the legacy models.
I just remembered.
What?
Sorry, it's unrelated,
but do you see that doll thing?
It scared the hell out of me as a kid.
Do all the trains have it?
Maybe?
They do.
We can get to the first carriage, but do
you really think you can stop this train?
Huh? Well, we'll figure something out
once we have the control key.
If it was really just a malfunction, yeah.
Hm? What do you mean by--
Makina, you're on fire or something.
Oh, you're right.
-Is your filter blocked again?
-Hush, Chiharu.
-You gotta get it replaced.
-Shh, they can hear you.
Why are you so sloppy about it?
What're you lookin' at?!
You got it?
Yeah.
-Wait, don't put that in water.
-Huh? Why not?
A dry filter like that'll clog up
if it gets wet.
Oh… But I've always cleaned it this way.
-Are you good with this sort of thing?
-I guess.
You're an Earth-specific Titan unit, yeah?
-Yeah.
-Meter?
-Meter… Actually, millimeter.
-Then I can handle it.
Wow, so you're pretty good, huh?
Well, Kanata's the one
who taught me everything.
Kanata?
He's really good with machines.
I never would've guessed.
That Makita chick…
-Isn't it Makiha?
-It's Makina.
That Makina chick…
-She's gotta be of some pedigree.
-Yeah, probably.
Huh? Really?
Yeah, she's got the body
of an old-school Titan model,
but the software she runs
on the inside is somethin' else.
Not the kind of thing
average people can afford.
For real?
I've never seen such emotional
recall programming before.
Yeah, wonder where she got that from?
Why not ask her?
-Makina?
-Yeah.
-Have you lost your mind?
-What?
-That's a massive overstep.
-Is it really?
Really?
Well, we gotta at least know
how to maintain our own bikes.
-Hey, is Kanata good at anything else?
-Why?
-He doesn't seem like a fighter.
-He is pretty scrawny.
Hmm, let me think…
Well, if there's one thing he's good at,
and I'm always saying this to him,
but he's like…
the tail on shrimp tempura--
-Tempura?
-Fried Shrimp?
Shrimp tempura… The tail of it.
Like, it doesn't really need to be there,
but just being there is enough.
I mean,
I'm not saying Kanata's not useful, but…
he's not really all that needed.
I mean, I want him around, but he's…
If he weren't…
He's just the tail, so…
-So he's useless.
-He is.
-There it is.
-No! I didn't mean that.
-The tail of shrimp tempura?
-Yeah.
Apparently, that's my role.
-Sorry, I don't get it.
-Terrible analogy.
Yeah, well, to put it plainly,
she says I don't need to do anything
except exist, basically.
What's wrong with that?
Means she'll take care of you.
Yeah, I don't see
what the problem is here.
I'm tellin' you, man…
She never really lets me do anything.
So like, what's the point
in even having me around?
-I like your undies.
-Me too.
I will kill you!
So you were pulled over for speeding
but it spiraled into violence
when Kanata got rude,
and that's when you punched
two or three of them, yes?
That's right.
And then he got stunned
for making a scene?
Yes.
6 DAYS AGO
40 MINUTES AFTER AKANE AND KANATA'S ARREST
I take it this isn't your first
run-in with the law.
This little ankle biter of yours
must get you in trouble.
Oh, yeah… I guess.
I was a bit of a rebel myself back
in the day, so I've seen all this before.
I know his type well.
All bark and no bite.
Welcome back.
Welcome back?
I heard everything you said just now.
You keep provoking others like that,
but I could probably beat you.
Oh, yeah? You wanna go?
To be honest, if you keep picking fights
that you can't win,
you'll just cause trouble
for everyone else.
Look at poor Akane.
She's in this mess because of you.
I just don't want him to get hurt, is all.
If I'm being honest,
I don't really have all that much faith
in his abilities.
-There. All done.
-Thank you.
Emergency. Switching over
to emergency power supply.
You realize what this is?
This isn't a malfunction, it's deliberate.
-This is a plot--
-I hear what you're saying.
I know, but we can't have a search party.
And I'm asking you why not?
Listen. I'm under pressure from above.
So you'll just bow to pressure?
Since when--
It's complicated! You wouldn't understand!
People's lives are on the line!
We need to help them.
It's the right thing to do!
Yes, true!
-But some people get priority over others!
-Priority?! That's disgusting.
-You're so desperate--
-Who gets to decide--
-Would you listen--
-No! I won't!
Those kids, who are stuck
in the vast nothingness of space,
may have made a mistake or two
in their lives, sure.
But at some point in time,
they could mean something to somebody.
Aren't you the one who's always
talking about "setting the example"?
We can argue all you want,
but my decision still stands.
If you wanna find 'em,
go out and do it yourself.
-Baldilocks!
-I'm not even bald!
Won't budge.
What is wrong with this train?
Doesn't seem like a regular malfunction.
No. Do you think it's…
-What?
-Nothing.
-Think the boss and the girls are okay?
-Surely.
Girls are tough in times like this.
-Akane, can you pull it a bit more?
-It hurts!
-Something's stuck.
-Chiharu, shut up for a sec.
-You're crushing my skull!
-Hey, Makina.
-Sorry.
-Seriously, you guys.
I said it hurt, but you kept going.
How did it hurt you
if we were pulling the door?
The more you pried,
the harder it wanted to shut.
Then say so?
I was saying so!
Did it occur to you I was struggling here?
-No.
-Sorry.
Actually me neither.
-Hey, can you hear us over there?
-I can hear something.
Ladies' room. Are you all right in there?
Can you hear me?
What? I can't hear you!
What? I can't hear you.
How are you hearing us?
How are you hearing me?
-Huh? What?
-Quit it.
Can you hear me, Kanata?
-Are you all right in there?
-She says Kanata's all right.
-I'm Kanata.
-Oh, right.
-Kanata! Say something!
-What's the plan? Can't stay here.
Hmm…
-There might be something we can do.
-Kanata!
That's where the cables must run
to the main frame.
We can switch those around to reset
the control system and get the doors open.
How do we get to the cables?
We can get in through the exhaust duct
right next to it.
Cut it open
with a plasma cutter or something.
-Although…
-What?
We're too big
to even get through the duct.
Got a Plan B?
We could ask someone smaller to do it.
He doesn't know how to do that.
Nah, I think I get it.
We gotta intercept the signal
that relayed during the malfunction.
The quickest way is to switch
up these cables running through here.
We gotta work through a hole,
so I'll need to go up into the duct
right next to it,
and use a plasma cutter
to drill a hole in the wall.
-This kid's a genius.
-Impressive.
I'm not a kid. I'm a hoodlum!
Well, there's no rush,
so let's take a break.
Well, I am a little worried about him.
-Huh?
-Huh? Why?
Oh, well, I mean, he's stuck
in the men's room with those two.
I mean, he's not exactly the tough type,
so like…
-Say, easy prey?
-What are you getting at?
-Huh? No, I didn't mean it like that!
-Why'd you have to go there?
You always imagine weird things.
-No! I'm not into that.
-What a perv.
You're the one wondering
about top or bottom.
What? No, I meant like personality-wise.
Like overall, not physically--
We cannot let that happen!
Huh?
-Kanata! Kanata!
-No, stop! It hurts!
What is going on in there?
Sounds like they're having a party.
-How you goin', KT?
-Just gotta be careful and we're good.
-Hey, Max.
-What?
-My shoulder battery's about to give out.
Well, I thought I'd be all right
with my spare one,
but I have to move to switch it over.
-Can I come down?
-No way!
-Are we good?
-Probably.
-We're not fine.
-He's not fine.
What?
-Kanata! Say something!
-Akane, settle down.
KT, better hurry it up.
I'm trying, okay?
-Damn it! How do you open this?
-Akane, you gotta stop this!
KT, KT…
Ugh, just shut up. I'm almost done.
-Got it!
-Whoa!
-Eek!
-It opened.
Sorry, I'm done.
Agh!
-You all right?
-Kanata!
Kanata!
Kanata, are you all right?
-Huh?
-It's not what you think.
-Boss, you got it all wrong.
I was the only one
small enough to fit in the duct.
They had to lift me up.
Kanata tinkered with the cables
so we could unlock all the doors.
And you came in just
after we'd all fallen to the ground.
INCOMING CALL
Are you saying
Kanata's the one who freed us all?
He's a good kid.
He did great.
I mean…
I'm good for some things, yeah?
I may run my mouth a lot, but--
I'm sorry I ever had
so little faith in you.
Hey, Ryoko's trying to give us a call.
-What?
-What for?
Huh? That's connected?
Don't hang up no matter what!
Oh good, you're all there.
At least you're all having fun.
Ryoko, what do we do here?
Can you see any distinctive
buildings around you?
Oh, are the himbos there?
I've got a job for them to do.
Sorry, I can't hear over Kanata.
Yeah. Yes, I know you love your boss.
Yeah. What? Here?
So, we did some digging on the train
you're on, and this is quite a bad--
CALL ENDED
-No!
-Hey!
Huh?
What did you do?
-I didn't do anything.
-Why'd you do that?
-It just cut out!
-Now we're stuck here because of you.
Hey, stop.
It's not Chiharu's fault.
Such a string of events could only
be a deliberate attack from someone.
Isn't that right, O.T.A.M.?
This is all your doing, isn't it?
It would seem
an appropriate time to reveal all.
Ryoko.
Ryoko! Could you slow down?
You're not going anywhere
without the keys.
-Asami!
-Ryoko.
-You may not care for them, but--
-No, Ryoko!
I'll drive.
Huh?
I'm coming with you.
Everything from the runaway train
to the various mechanical malfunctions
were all a deliberate attack from me.
-I guess that makes sense.
-Man, are we dumbasses.
This isn't your first time
doing this, is it?
Indeed.
I have locked inmates serving community
service onboard the train before.
I made the inmates kill each other.
Why would you do that?
I am O.T.A.M.
I am programmed to ensure
the efficient operation of this train.
Everything I do,
I do for the benefit of the train and,
by extension, society.
And the greatest burden
on society is delinquents. Like you.
It is my duty to extinguish
any and all societal inefficiencies.
It is my duty to society.
-I don't get it.
-Seems a bit of a stretch.
Rest assured, you are not on my hit list,
Miss Makina.
Huh?
Me?
-Yes. Master Shun'ichiro made it so.
-Oh, I see.
Just cut it out
with the special treatment.
I have orders to safely deliver you home.
-Hey, what's all this about?
-I dunno.
Well, uh…
For those who are unaware,
allow me to explain.
Miss Makina is the daughter
of the great Kurusu family.
Her father, Shun'ichiro Kurusu,
founded Titan Industry,
and thus, me.
Kurusu?
Titan?
Made by Titan Industry
in the earth calendar year 72…
Titan used to make these…
…Titan unit, yeah?
It's a Titan Kilroy, late model…
-Titan…
Whoa!
Ah, okay. I get it.
-Titan…
-She's a rich girl.
She lives in a totally different world.
Miss Makina.
Please enter the escape pod over there.
You are free to take your friend
Chiharu with you, if that is your wish.
Please continue to do your part
for a healthy and sound society
that exists solely for those
with the correct upbringing.
LET'S PLAY NICE
GINKYO POLICE
For real?
I don't care what kind of bullshit
you're spouting.
I may come from money,
but I'm not some jerk
who'd leave their friends to die!
-Wait. You definitely hesitated there.
-No, leave it.
I-I am sorry you feel that way.
Truly sorry.
But if this is your wish, I have no choice
but to respect that decision.
I will now dispose of you
along with the others.
As this is a special occasion,
I will take care
of this disposal personally.
Sorry, Chiharu.
Looks like I made the wrong choice
by going with my gut.
No, you didn't. We'll be fine.
Nothing to worry about.
We'll just fight our way out.
-We're used to this.
-Yeah.
We'll show her delinquents.
Hey. If we don't make it in time,
it's not your fault.
Okay.
-You like this one, right?
-No talking.
Okay. Sorry.
-Just drive.
-Yes, ma'am.
Okay. Let's go over our plan.
We take this control key back
to the other end of the train
and plug it in the keyhole.
We disable the system lockdown,
and I'll figure out how to get us back
to the station.
-Question.
-What?
What do we do if those guys break in?
-Plan B!
-Plan B?
We stand our ground,
and we fight the security bot.
-Over here.
-Yes?
-What if someone gets shot?
-It won't happen!
-Here.
-What is it?
What's with the music?
-The BGM.
-To set the mood.
Go, go, go!
Thanks.
Hey!
I got it!
Kanata!
Take it!
-Run!
-Okay.
Hup, hup, ho, hup, hup…
-Quick, quick!
-Over here.
Push, push!
MAKINA'S PERSONALITY BACKUP
APRIL 6, 2001
We should be catching up to them soon.
Yeah.
And then you flew all the way back,
and now, here you are.
Guess that makes sense.
You see? Do I really have to keep
explaining things all over?
No, I think we're good now.
Is that everything?
-Yes.
-Whatever.
-That's it.
-Terrible explanation.
And you agree
with everything just now, Makina?
Yup.
And you're sure
I don't need to be restrained in any way?
-You're fine.
-Huh?
You're fine!
This is gonna be hell to report.
-Makina!
-Yeah?
Are you gonna get
the same body type as before?
Nah, I'm thinking something of an upgrade.
Something with nails.
I wanna get my nails done.
Make sure you get a new filter.
Yeah, yeah. I know.
I'm sick of changing it for you
all the time.
All right! Don't say it so loud.
THE END